ATHM Textile Industry Stereographs 6524/006 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II: General Images Organized by Textile Related Subject
  - Cotton (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Item 21: Cotton haulers. (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of four African American cotton pickers, one female and three male, carrying full baskets of cotton on their heads through a cotton field. Location unknown. Southern Steroscopic Views published by D. J. Ryan, Savannah, Ga. ca. 1875. 17.75 x 10 cm.
    - Item 22: Morning start in the Cotton Fields (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of a group of cotton pickers in a cotton field filling baskets with cotton. Most are men but a few are women. Two overseers on horseback watch in the background. Location unknown. Photographed and published by B. W. Kilburn, Littleton, New Hampshire, ca. 1892. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 23: The Cotton Pickers, 1876 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Winslow Homer, 1876 (Oil on canvas). Image depicts two African-American girls picking cotton in a field. Los Angeles, Calif.: Los Angeles County Museum of Art, ca. 1987. Postcard written in 1998. 15 x 11 cm.
    - Item 24: Cotton is king, a plantation scene (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Cotton is king, a plantation scene. Black-and-white image of cotton picking on a plantation. Scene shows piles of cotton in foreground with a basket off to the side. A boy in the foreground appears to be emptying his bag into the pile of cotton. A little girl in a dress is shown sitting on the ground on the right. More workers are picking cotton in the background. All appear to be African American with the exception of the little girl. Niagara Falls, N.Y.: M. H. Zahner, Publisher, ca. 1900. Sold only by Griffith & Griffith. 17.75 x 8.75 cm. See Item 17, in this folder, for the same image but in color, with the caption "Cotton Plantatiaon Scene," and Item 18, in this folder, for the same image in color but reversed, with the caption "Cotton is King."
    - Item 25: Cotton is King--Plantation Scene with Pickers at Work, Georgia (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Cotton is King--Plantation Scene with Pickers at Work, Georgia. Black-and-white image of African American workers, both male and female, filling baskets with cotton in a cotton field. An overseer on horseback watches in the background. The United States produces more than half of the world's cotton. The annual output is now nearly 12,000,000 bales of 500 pounds each, worth at the plantation approximately $1,800,000,000. It is the country's largest export. Meadville, Pa.: Keystone View Company, ca. 1900-1920. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 26: Cotton Field and Pickers (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of two African American children standing by a basket of cotton amid rows and rows of cotton. More workers depicted in background. Location unknown, but most likely in or near Savannah, Ga. Savannah, Ga.: J. N. Wilson, Photographer and Publisher of the finest selection of stereoscopic views in the South, ca. 1880. 17.75 x 10 cm.
    - Item 27: Picking Cotton on a Mississippi Plantation (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of a young girl and small child in foreground with a basket of cotton. More workers seen in the background with one person sitting on top of sacks. The cotton field shown in the image may yield 400 pounds to the acre. Meadville, Pa.: Keystone View Company, ca. 1900-1920. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 28: Picking cotton on a great plantation in North Carolina (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image depicts African American men and women picking cotton on a plantation in North Carolina. Note the boy sitting in the cotton basket in the foreground. North Bennington, Vt.: H.C. White Co., ca. 1907. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 29: A Typical Texas Cotton Field at Picking Time (Box 7, Folder 4)
      A Typical Texas Cotton Field at Picking Time. Black- and-white image of cotton pickers, both male and female. Little girl in bandana in foreground putting cotton into a sack. Other workers seen in the background, along with a young boy. All are African American. Picking begins in late August and may last until Christmas. The small girl may pick twenty pounds of lint in a day, while an expert picker can gather as much as 300 pounds. Meadville, Pa.: Keystone View Company, ca. 1900-1920. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 30: Cotton Field and Pickers (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of a group of cotton pickers, including a man, woman, and young boy and girl in foreground. Other pickers in background. All are African American. Buildings visible in background. No location given. ca. 1900. 17.75 x 10 cm.
    - Item 31: Cotton Picking, Mississippi, U.S.A. (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of workers, both male and female, in the field picking cotton, loading it into bags or baskets. One man in the background carries a loaded basket on his shoulders. A young girl in the foreground is filling a basket with cotton. All the workers are African American. No location given. ca. 1900. 17.25 x 9 cm.
    - Item 32: Picking Cotton, Louisiana (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of man bent over picking cotton with a small boy standing near him, both surrounded by rows and rows of cotton plants. Both are African American. Another worker in the background. Littleton, New Hampshire: Littleton View Co., Publishers, ca. 1880-1889. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 33: A Field of Cotton (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of two women posed in the middle of a large cotton field but they do not appear to be actually picking cotton (they have no cotton bags for instance). Buildings and trees in the background. ca. 1907-1915. 13.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 34: Busy in the Cotton Field (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of two African American children picking cotton in a large cotton field, with several other pickers visible in the background. Trees in the background at the edge of the cotton field. No location given. ca. 1907-1915. 13.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 35: Picking Cotton (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image depicts several African American women in a cotton field: one woman places cotton in a basket, with a child sitting on the ground in front of the basket; another carries carries a basket of cotton on her head; and a third (on the left) fills a basket of bag with cotton. Two African American men stand in the background. Probably in the Savannah, Ga., area. O. Pierre Havens (successor to Wilson & Havens), Photographer, Savannah, Ga. ca. 1883-1888. 17.75 x 10 cm.
    - Item 36: Cotton Picking, Louisiana, 1892 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Cotton Picking, Louisiana. Black-and-white image of two African American cotton pickers in the foreground, and another with a basket hoisted on his shoulder filled with cotton. The pickers in the background appear to be Caucasian; most of them are women wearing sunbonnets. Washington, D.C.: Published by J. F. Jarvis; sold only by Underwood & Underwood. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 37: Cotton Field (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of cotton pickers in a cotton field. Almost all appear to be African American. The man in the foreground carries a basket filled with cotton on his head. A child walks beside him. House and trees in background. Probably in the Aiken, S.C., area. No. 170 of "Characteristic Southern Scenes." Photographed by J. A. Palmer, Aiken, S.C. ca. 1880s. See also Items 38 and 39, in this folder, which show the same house in the background although it is unclear if they were all taken at the same time. 17.75 x 10 cm.
    - Item 38: Cotton Field (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of several African American women picking cotton in a cotton field. Two small children are nearby. Two of the women carry filled baskets of cotton on their heads. House and trees in background. Probably in the Aiken, S.C., area. No. 175 of "Characteristic Southern Scenes." Photographed by J. A. Palmer, Aiken, S.C. ca. 1880s. See also Items 37 and 39, in this folder, which show the same house in the background although it is unclear if they were all taken at the same time. 17.75 x 10 cm.
    - Item 39: Cotton Field (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of an African American woman with a basket filled with cotton on her head in the foreground. Several workers can be seen picking cotton in the background. House and trees in the background. Probably in the Aiken, S.C., area. No. 177 of "Characteristic Southern Scenes." Photographed by J. A. Palmer, Aiken. S.C. ca. 1880s. See also Items 37 and 38, in this folder, which show the same house in the background although it is unclear if they were all taken at the same time. 17.75 x 10 cm.
    - Item 40: Cotton Plantation of J. L. Thornton, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Alexander City, Ala. Color image of a cotton field in the foreground with a horse-drawn wagon filled with cotton and two pickers shown standing on the wagon. One man shown near the lead horses and more pickers shown in back. Published by Barton and Allen. Postmarked Sept. 30, 1914 in Woburn, Mass. 13.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 41: Picking Cotton (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of cotton pickers in a field of cotton. Older man with a young woman and child in the foreground. Several pickers in the field. All are African American. Buildings and telephone poles in background. Raphael Tuck & Sons' Post Card Series No. 1098, "Dixie Land." Printed in Germany. Postmarked Dec. 24, 190[?] in Aiken, S.C.; manufactured between 1902 and 1907. 14 x 9 cm. See Item 57, in this folder, for a close-up view of the older man on the left, with different colored clothes, no publisher given, and identified as New Orleans, La.
    - Item 42: Cotton Harvest (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of large mound of cotton in foreground, in front of a wagon in a cotton field. An African American man stands with his hand on the wagon and another man is in the wagon with a basket of cotton. Trees seen in the background. Location unknown. C.T. Photochrom card. ca. 1907-1915. 13.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 43: Gathering Cotton The Old Way and the New (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of two separate scenes. Scene on left shows two pickers filling long dragging sacks with cotton. Scene on the right shows a man operating a machine to gather the cotton. Printed on reverse: "While the old method of filling long dragging sacks is still used in the South, the modern mechanical handling enables today's cotton workers to gather manyfold over the quantity possible by hand pickers." Card made in USA by E.C. Kropp Co., Milwaukee, Wis. ca. 1950. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 44: In the Cotton Field (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of a man weighing a bale of cotton. The scale is attached to the wagon in the field. Another man is sitting on the ground by the wagon and several pickers can be seen in the background, along with an overseer on horseback. Location unknown. ca. 1907-1915. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 45: Cotton Picking Time (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image shows three mechanical cotton pickers, each with a driver. One man stands in front of the middle cotton picker. On the left is an open railroad car-size trailer full of cotton. Printed on reverse: "Greetings from Dixieland! The modern cotton pickers offer sharp contrast to the back-breaking job of hand picking cotton." Mechanical cotton pickers were introduced in the South in the late 1940s. National Post Card Service, Sebring, Fla. [after 1963] 14 X 9 cm.
    - Item 46: Cotton Picking Scene, Oklahoma City, Okla., 1908 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of Caucasian cotton pickers--men, women, and children--being photographed amid a field of cotton. In the background are two wagons filled with cotton and two men standing on top of them. Souvenir Post Card Co., New York. Printed in Germany. Postmarked Oct. 5, 1908 in Oklahoma [City], Okla. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 47: A Texas Cotton Field, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of cotton pickers, both Caucasian and African American, dragging sacks of cotton in the field as they pick. One of the pickers is a child. Printed on reverse: "A Texas cotton field. Thousands of scenes similar to this make Texas the leading cotton state in the U.S. It produces more than 2,800,000 bales (500 pounds each) yearly on its rich, alluvial lands. Enormous crops find their way to New England mills and to Europe, and yield about $116,000,000 annually. Cotton-seed exceeds 600,000 tons, employing innumerable oil mills." Raphael Tuck & Sons' Post Card Series No. 2378, "Dallas, Texas." Postmarked April 3, 1907 in San Antonio, Tex. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 48: Cotton Picken Time in the South, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of cotton pickers bent over picking cotton in the field. Blue skies and trees depicted in background. No location given. Robert Thomas, P.O. Box 405, Thomasville, Georgia [photographer?]. Plastichrome by Colourpicture Publishers, Inc., Boston 15, Mass. USA. Postmarked Mar. 30, 1956 in Fort Lauderdale, Fla. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 49: Cotton Picking, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of African American pickers, three men and one woman, in the field with baskets of cotton. Horse and wagon and trees depicted in background. Published by Carter & Gut, N.Y., for the Kress Stores. Postmarked Sept. 18, 1905 in Rome, Georgia. 14 x 9 cm. See Item 53, in this folder, for what appears to be the same image, but with different coloring of the clothes, a slightly different pose of the man in the middle, and a different publisher.
    - Item 50: Old Time Pine Log Hut, Macon, Ga. (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of log cabin with an African American woman and three children in doorway of cabin, presumed to be cotton pickers. Flowering shrubs in foreground. Raphael Tuck & Sons' Post Card Series No. 2074 "Macon, Ga." Dated Sept. 11, 1903 on front. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 51: Cotton Pickers At Work, in Dixieland, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of several pickers in the field, all bent over picking cotton. Published by Asheville Post Card Co., Asheville, N.C. Postmarked June 3, 1946 in Lake City, Fla. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 52: Picking cotton (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of many pickers in the field, most of whom appear to be African American, filling baskets of cotton. A wagon with men loading the cotton is depicted on the right. An overseer on horseback is in the background. ca. 1907-1915. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 53: Cotton Picking, Pinehurst, N.C. (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of a half dozen cotton pickers, all African American, bent over picking cotton in the field. Two large baskets filled with cotton are shown in foreground. E. L. Merrow, Publ. Postmarked Feb. 23, [1920?] in Pinehurst, N.C. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 53: In the Cotton Field, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of African American pickers, three men and one woman, in the field with baskets of cotton. Horse and wagon and trees depicted in background. E. C. Kropp, Publ., Milwaukee, Wis. Dated March 11, 1905, Augusta (Ga.?); postmarked March 13, 1905 in Springfield, Mass. 14 x 9 cm. See Item 49, in this folder, for what appears to be the same image, but with different coloring of the clothes, a slightly different pose of the man in the middle, and a different publisher.
    - Item 54: Picking Cotton, Arizona (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of pickers filling long sacks with cotton. Wagon with a man standing on top loading cotton on the right. Two men are shown weighing the cotton. Published by Harry Herz, 754 E. Culver St., Phoenix, Arizona. ca. 1915-1930. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 55: Mammoth Lodi Cotton (Valdosta, Georgia), 1910 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of a man standing on a stepladder to pick cotton from a tall cotton plant. Printed on the botton of the card: "Mammoth Lodi Cotton. 'Eight bales to the acre, and they say there isn't any money in cotton.'" Mammoth Lodi cotton is presumably a reference to a particular variety of cotton plant, one that grows quite tall. Copyright H. W. Brown, Tifton, Ga. Valdosta, Ga. printed on reverse of card. Postmarked Nov. 26, 1910 in Valdosta, Ga. 9 x 14 cm.
    - Item 56: Cotton Picking, Savannah, Georgia (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of cotton pickers in the field. Some pickers in the foreground are shown with baskets on their shoulders. Trees shown in background. ca. 1890 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 57: "De Lan' O' Cotton," New Orleans, La. (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of an older African American man picking cotton and putting it into his sack. A woman is off the the side watching him. A wooden building is in the background. F. L. Howe, Atlanta [photographer?]. ca. 1907-1915. 8.75 x 13.5 cm. See Item 41, in this folder, for this same man in a wider view, with different colored clothes, and no location given.
    - Item 58: Cotton Picking Time, Southern Pines, N.C., 1914 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of several African American women bent over picking cotton. A rather ramshackle cabin is in the background, with another smaller cabin to the right. Hand colored postcard. Published by Eddy's Studio, Southern Pines, N. C. Copyright 1914 by E. C. Eddy, Southern Pines, N.C. Postmarked Jan. 25, 1940 in Southern Pines, N.C. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 59: Picking Cotton, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of three African American men in the field, filling sacks with cotton. Dated March 15, 1905 in Augusta, Ga.; postmarked March 15, 1905 in Augusta, and March 17, 1905 in Springfield, Mass. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 60: Picking Cotton (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of three African American adults filling long sacks with cotton. In the foreground are three children alongside the adults. Unknown location. ca. 1907-1915. 13.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 61: Picking Cotton (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of several African American men and women in the field picking cotton, including some children. One woman in front with a red dress and a big straw hat is shown filling her sack. The man in front seems to be inspecting more than picking. Unknown location. ca. 1907-1915. 14 X 9 cm.
    - Item 62: Picking Cotton, 1904 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of African Americans picking cotton, primarily men but at least one woman is visible. A large basket in the foreground is filled with cotton. Postmarked March 3, 1904 in Augusta, Ga., and March 5, 1904 in Springfield, Mass. 8 x 14 cm.
    - Item 63: Cotton is King, Plantation Scene, Georgia, U.S.A., 1895 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of African American cotton pickers--men, women, and at least one child--in a field picking cotton. Overseer on horseback in the background. Small child with her hand in the basket in the foreground. Title is printed on reverse in English, French, German, Spanish, Swedish, and Russian. New York: Underwood & Underwood. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 64: Picking Cotton, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of Afrrican American cotton pickers, all male, filling large sacks of cotton in large cotton field. An overseer on horseback is in the background. Unknown location. Copyright 1906 by Detroit Publishing Co. 14 X 9 cm.
    - Item 65: Pickers Grouped in Cotton Field, 1892 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of a group of African American cotton pickers, all men, but also one young girl and one young boy. Two of the pickers have their hats tucked into their suspenders. Unknown location. Littleton, New Hampshire: Photographed and published by B. W. Kilburn. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 66: Our Little Cotton Coop, 1892 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of small African American child with a filled sack of cotton in front of him in the foreground. Older man behind him, along with several other pickers, all African American. Woman picker in background. Littleton, New Hampshire: Photographed and published by B. W. Kilburn. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 67: A Typical Cotton Picking Scene (Arkansas) (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of five pickers, most of whom appear to be African American, bending over to pick and stuff cotton into their extremely long sacks. Printed on reverse: "An everyday scene during cotton picking time deep down in the 'Land of Cotton.' Cotton and its by-products are one of Arkansas' most important industries." MWM Color-Litko "Bursheen" Finished, made only by MWM - Aurora, Mo. ca. 1930-1944. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 68: Georgia's cotton crop, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of a cotton harvesting machine. Printed on reverse: "Georgia's cotton crop grown by 40,000 farmers is now produced and harvested almost entirely by machine. Georgia has 220 gins which separate the fiber from the seed. Approximately 100 cotton mills spin and weave the fiber into yarns and cloth and 200 manufacturing plants transform it into the many articles of clothing, household goods and furnishings to which cotton is so well adapted. The Agricultural Commodity Commission for Cotton sponsors Research, Education, and Promotion in an effort to have more people enjoy the benefits of Cool, Comfortable, Carefree Cotton. This picture was taken at the Southeast Georgia Branch Experiment Station of the University of Georgia College of Agriculture." Burman Printing Co., Athens, Ga. Postmarked Dec. 15, 1976 in Georgia. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 69: Cotton ready for shipment (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of a huge pile of cotton bales, sitting atop a wagon or possibly an open railroad car, ready to be shipped. The visible bales are stacked six high. No location given. ca. 1915-1930. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 70: Loading Cotton, Galveston Wharf., 1907 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Black-and-white image of a ship being loaded with bales of cotton in Galveston, Texas. Dock worker in foreground loading bales, which are pulled up a ramp by a pulley. Trubf Photo. Dated January 16, 1907, postmarked January 16, 1907 in Galveston. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 71: A Cotton Sample Room, Meridian, Mississippi, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of a cotton sample room in Meridian, Miss. Scene depicts long tables filled with cotton; several workers stand around the tables. Cubbyhole shelving in background of room. Many cotton bits on the floor. Published by S.H. Kress & Co. Postmarked April 25, 1911 in Meridian. 13 x 9 cm.
    - Item 72: Samples taken from cotton bales in Factors Room, where sales are made by samples and the original bales are delivered, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image depicts several long tables covered with cotton samples. More bales are piled up along the walls. No location given. Published by The Acmegraph Co., Chicago, Ill. Postmarked Nov. 21, 1912 in Ridlonville, Me. 13.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 73: Cotton Sample Room, Vicksburg, Miss., 1921 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of the interior of a cotton sample room showing several workers and long tables filled with samples of cotton. Message on reverse includes this language: "These 'samples' are cut from the bales of cotton in the warehouses, and from them the cotton-buyers make their purchases." Published by International Post Card Co., New York. Postmarked July 4, 1921 in Vicksburg. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 74: Weighing Cotton (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of men weighing cotton bales. Several workers, some of whom are African American, shown standing around the scales. Man in coat and hat with his back to the camera may be a supervisor of some sort. No location given. Publ. by T. P. & Co., N.Y. Made in Germany. 1907-1915. 14 x 9 cm.
    - Item 75: Weighing Cotton, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Color image of a group of African American pickers, both men and women, standing around a scale in the cotton field, as a basket of cotton is being weighed by an older, Caucasian man. No location given. C.T. American Art. Postmarked April 5, 1920 in Southern Pines, N.C. 14 x 9 cm.